# Rachel M. Sokol

## **Security Evangelist**

#### Rachel Marie Sokol (she/her)

**Certifications**: A+, Net+, Sec+, CySA+, AWS Cloud Practitioner, CEH, ISC2 CC, CISSP (anticipated June 2023) **Washington, District of Columbia** 

443.847.0489 Sokolcyber@gmail.com

### **Summary**

Tech generalist with over 15 years experience. True passion for service and sharing knowledge with others. I've helped over 200 students get technical certifications from CompTIA and AWS. Very interested in pursuing security analytics or engineering,

#### **Experience**

#### Per Scholas / Technical Instructor

May 2019 - August 2022, NCR Region

Facilitated cybersecurity classes. Lesson planned. Created activities and games to explain foundational concepts. 62% certification rate. 70% graduation rate Tools: Google Suites, Github, Canvas, Salesforce, OneLogon, CertMaster

#### **Telenet** / Marketing Specialist

October 2016 - April 2018, Athens, Georgia

Contracted for Dell. Marketed enterprise servers, networking equipment, and software solutions to small and medium sized businesses. 56% lead conversion. Tools: ServiceNow, Oracle, Office Suite

## Beaufort-Jasper Equal Opportunity Commission / Jr Network

Administrator January 2016 -

September 2016, Beaufort/Jasper County, South Carolina

Assisted with full network and workstation upgrade to move records to electronic platforms. **Tools: Cisco Switches and Hubs, Linux OS, SonicWall, Fortinet** 

#### **Education**

## WGU / Masters of Cybersecurity and Information Assurance

Fall 2021 - June 2023,

Noteworthy Courses: Tactical Management, Ethical Hacking, CS Architecture & Engineering; Forthcoming degree anticipated June 2023.

#### Towson University / Bachelor of Science Sociology

August 2007 - December 2012, Baltimore, Maryland

Teaching Assistant for 2 years for Whitney Garcia's Sociological Theory course, Departmental Recognitions and Award, Alpha Kappa Delta